STREET INTERVIEW - ANNOYING BOSSES!
（レポーター）
今日は ここ渋谷(しぶや)に来ております！
Today, we're here in Shibuya.
今回のテーマは“ムカつく上司！”
早速 聞いてまいりましょう！
Our topic is "annoying bosses."
Let's get to it!
あっ！ そこの黄色い女性の方！
How about you, lady with the yellow fur?
What kind of work do you do?
お仕事 何をされてますか？
（女性）あっ あの… ＯＬです
I'm an office worker.
（レポーター）
職場にムカつく上司 いますよね？
You have an annoying boss, right?
（女性）えー まあ いますね
Well, yeah.
（レポーター）それは どんな？
What kind?
（女性）えっと…
Well,
there's one who unloads work on me just
before it's time to leave for the day.
終業間際に いきなり仕事を
たくさん押しつけてくる人とか…
ハッハッハ！ ありがちですね
That does happen, doesn't it?
（女性）
もっと早く言えよ～ みたいな
It's like,
"You could have asked me earlier!"
なるほど～ お時間 頂き
ありがとうございまし…
I see! Thanks for taking the time to...
（女性）あと 女ってだけで
バカにしてくる人とか
And there's one who makes fun of me
just because I'm a woman,
even though he bends over backwards
for the girl who flatters him.
そのくせ こび売ってる女に
甘かったりとか
全然 仕事してないくせに
無駄に汗ばっかり かいてたりとか
And he works up a sweat from goofing off!
だいぶ不満が
たまってるようですね
You seem to have a lot of complaints.
ありがとうござい…
Thank you very...
I hope your ears are burning!
You lazy male chauvinist
Waste of flesh!
RAGE
♪～
～♪
（プー子(こ)）実は今度 日本で―
Actually, I was thinking I might
start a business here in Japan.
ビジネス始めてみようかなって
思ってて
輸入雑貨屋
An imported goods store.
You want in, Retsuko?
烈子(れつこ)も一緒に やんない？
（烈子）やばい…
Wow...
An imported goods store.
輸入雑貨屋…
何て夢のある響き！
It sounds like a dream!
魅惑的すぎる～！
It's too alluring!
（カバ恵(え)）あら？ 烈子ちゃん
何か いいことでもあったの？
What's this?
Retsuko, did something good happen?
べ… 別に何も
Nothing in particular.
ほんとに？
Really?
何でもないですよ…
It's nothing.
ほんとにいいい～？
Really?
烈子ちゃんの瞳の奥に
暗く長いトンネルが見える
I can see a long, dark tunnel
through the back of your eyes.
この笑顔が意味するのは―
The meaning behind that smile is...
暗闇からの解放
a release from darkness,
自由
freedom.
How is it that she can
accurately read my mind?
（烈子）何で この人
的確に 私の心を読んでくるの！？
This middle-aged woman
is a rumor-spreading pro.
このおばちゃんは うわさ話のプロ
私から 転職のにおいを
嗅ぎつけたら―
If she picks up the scent
that I might change jobs,
会社中に うわさを
ばらまくに決まってる！
the rumor will spread
all over the company.
んも～ カバ恵さんには
隠し事できないなあ！
I can't hide anything from you,
Mrs. Kabae!
実は ここ５日ほど
その…
The truth is, I haven't been
able to poop for five days.
出るものが
出てなくて―
今日の朝やっと…
-But this morning, it happened.
-You unplugged the long, dark tunnel?
暗く長いトンネルを抜けて？
そうそうそう！
That's right!
I knew it!
やっぱりね～！
That's the face you were making.
そんな顔してた
（烈子）ハア…
危なかった…
That was close.
（フェネ子(こ)）あっ 烈子
Oh, Retsuko.
便秘 治ったんだって？ よかったね
I heard your constipation cleared up.
Good for you.
（烈子）もう広まってんのかよ…
It's already spreading...
Also, I saw you...
あとさ 私 見ちゃった
（烈子）ん？
（フェネ子）
こないだ 昼の
ＯＬ番組でやってた―
on afternoon TV, in an interview
about "annoying bosses."
〝ムカつく上司！〞の
街頭インタビュー
なっ… 何の話？
What are you talking about?
There was a mosaic over your face,
but it was you, wasn't it?
（フェネ子）
顔にモザイク入ってたけど―
あれ 烈子でしょ？
Me, on TV?
私がテレビに？ ないないない
No way! I haven't even been
to Shibuya recently!
最近 渋谷なんて行ってないし
Shibuya?
渋谷？
私 渋谷って言ったっけ？
Did I mention Shibuya?
えっ… さっき言ってたよ…
You did, not long ago.
Is that right?
あっ そう
She looked just like you.
じゃ 他人の空似か
Apparently so!
じゃないかな～
アハッ アハハハ…
Now I've done it!
（烈子）うかつだった～！
I've been far too careless,
ever since I met with Puko.
プー子に会ってから
ちょっと浮かれ過ぎてたかも
気を付けよう
I have to be careful.
（トン）んん～
（ハイ田(だ)）烈子！
Retsuko!
Haida, what's wrong?
ハ… ハイ田君 どうしたの？
烈子 お前…
Retsuko! You...
昨日 出産したってマジか！？
Is it true you gave birth yesterday?
（烈子）はあ！？
難産だったって聞いたぞ！
-I heard it was a difficult delivery!
-Hey! When have I ever looked pregnant?
ちょっと待って
出産するわけないでしょ！
ハハハハハハ…
Fenneko, stop laughing!
（烈子）フェネ子 笑い過ぎ！
どこで どう 話が曲がったのか
知らないけど―
I don't know where
or how the story got twisted,
but it was originally
a different story, so...
それ 元は違う話だから
Is that right?
そっか…
ハア… びっくりした…
Oh, that was a scare.
そっかあ…
I see, now.
で 曲がる前は
どういう話だったんだ？
So what was the story
before it got twisted?
ハハハハハハ…
I said, stop laughing!
（烈子）だから 笑い過ぎ！
（坪根(つぼね)）若い人は いいわね
Young people have it good.
It looks like you're having fun.
楽しそうで
烈子さん
Retsuko...
a word...
ちょっと
（坪根）
ここ！ ここと ここと ここ！
Here! Here and here and here!
This is also wrong!
ここも間違ってる！
I'm sorry...
（烈子）すみません…
どうしちゃったの？
最近 たるんでらっしゃるわね
What's wrong?
You've been sluggish lately, haven't you?
I wonder what it is
you're showing up to work for.
一体 何しに
会社に来てるのかしら？
仕事です
My job.
Oh? I thought you were here to play.
はあ？ 遊びに来てるんでしょ？
だから 会社で
こんな顔ができるんでしょ！？
That's why you can make
this kind of face at work, isn't it?
ほら とっても楽しそう
Oh, it truly does look fun. How nice!
いいわね～
遊んで お金がもらえるなんて
To think you get paid for playing!
（烈子）
確かに間違ったのは私だけど…
It's true that I'm the one
who made mistakes, but...
Well, it was stupid of me
to ask you to do it.
まっ あんたに頼んだ
私がバカだったわ
Because all you do is waste time!
だって時間を
無駄にされるだけなんだもの
（烈子）
もともと あんたの担当分を―
That wasn't my work to do
in the first place, it was yours.
（烈子）
もともと あんたの担当分を―
（坪根）大体ね
私が若いころは―
私に むちゃぶりしてきた
仕事じゃん…
それは
厳しい時代だったのよ
私 何で我慢してるの？
Why am I putting up with this?
前々から言おうとは
思ってたんだけど…
烈子さん
Retsuko.
烈子さん！
Retsuko!
聞いてるの！？
Are you listening?
（烈子）そんなに言うなら―
If it's that big a problem...
shouldn't you have done it yourself
from the start?
最初から ご自分で
おやりになったら―
いいじゃないですか
あなた何を言ったか分かってるの？
Do you know what you're saying?
（烈子）言ってやった
I said it.
There's no going back.
もう あとには引けない
もう真面目な いい子には戻れない
No more being a serious, good girl.
KARAOKE
（烈子）言ってやった
I said it.
言ってやった
I said it!
I really said it!
私は言ってやった
♪～
I am triumphant!
上司に かみつくなんて
やるじゃん！
You talked back to your boss?
That's great!
いやあ…
No...
ちょっと大人げなかったかな
It didn't feel very grown up.
いや いいよ
うん いいバイブス
No, it's good! Good vibes.
エヘヘ…
ねえ プー子
こないだの話なんだけど
Hey, Puko. About what
you were saying the other day...
（プー子）ん？
輸入雑貨屋の店舗って
どこで開くつもりなの？
Where are you planning
to open the imported goods shop?
ああ 店舗？
Oh... the shop?
それは…
That's...
あっ 待って 私 当てる
Oh! Wait. I'll guess.
下北沢(しもきたざわ)！
Shimokitazawa!
まさか三茶(さんちゃ)！？
だったら近くていいな
It's not Sancha, is it?
That would be nice and close to me!
じゃあ…
Then...?
ないよ 店舗
There is no shop.
えっ？
Eh?
だから 店舗ないって
What I said. There's no shop.
Sorry! Didn't I tell you?
ごっめん 言ってなかったっけ？
じゃあ どうやって？
Then... how...?
ネット販売
Internet sales.
知り合いに頼んで
サイト立ち上げてさ
I asked an acquaintance
to set up a website.
だって最初から
リスク しょえないでしょ？
I can't risk unpaid rent
right off the bat, can I?
在庫は自分の家に置いとけばいいし
All I've got to do
is keep the stock at home.
もちろん さきざき
店舗 持てたら 最高だね
Of course, it would be nice
to get a shop in the future.
んっ
どうした？
What's wrong?
えっと ちなみに
お給料とかって？
What about the pay?
There won't be much
until the business gets rolling.
商売が軌道に乗るまでは
厳しいかもね
My monthly rent might be a problem.
私の月々の家賃
どうすればいいのかなあ？
Why not move out of your apartment?
Your parents live nearby, don't they?
アパート引き払っちゃえば？
実家 近いでしょ？
いらっしゃいませー
Welcome!
あら～ 烈子ちゃん
何か悪いことでもあったの？
Oh, dear.
Did something bad happen, Retsuko?
（烈子）ちょっと…
I've just learned about
the harshness of reality.
現実の厳しさを知りまして…
（角田(つのだ)）せんぱ～い！
Retsuko!
あっ 角田さん
Oh, Tsunoda.
Is it true that
you're leaving the company?
会社 辞めちゃうって
ほんとですか～？
何でですか？ 結婚ですか？
転職ですか？
Why? Are you getting married?
Are you switching jobs?
Going on a journey of self-discovery?
今更 自分探しですか～？
（烈子）それ 誰から聞いたの？
Who did you hear that from?
From Kabae in Accounting, but...
経理のカバ恵さんからですけど…
Retsuko?
先輩？
Kabae!
（烈子）カバ恵さ～ん！
（鷲美(わしみ)）
リアクションくらい取ったら？
You could at least show a reaction.
ううっ… ううっ…
私のお給料が～！
月々の固定費が～！
My salary!
My monthly fixed costs!
どうしたの？ 烈子ちゃん
落ち着いて
What's wrong? Retsuko, calm down!
私が辞めるって うわさ
広めないでください
Please don't spread the rumor
that I'm quitting.
確かに私 おしゃべり妖怪だから
拡散力には定評があるわよ
Certainly, I may be a chatterbox, and
my ability to spread rumors is legendary.
だけど さすがに烈子ちゃんの
立場を悪くするような―
But I wouldn't spread
a bad rumor like that,
悪いうわさを広めたりしない
which would put you in a bad position.
でも角田さんが…
But... Tsunoda said...
ごめんね
I'm sorry!
角田さんだけには言ったの
Tsunoda is the only one I told.
だって あなたたち 仲良しでしょ？
Because you two are good friends, right?
いやあ 別に… 仲は そんなに…
No, we're not that close.
私は小宮(こみや)さんから聞いて
角田さんに伝えた
I heard it from Komiya.
And I told Tsunoda.
That's all. That's the truth.
それだけ ほんとよ
小宮さん！？
Komiya?
どうして 小宮さんが…
Why would Komiya say that...?
（小宮）
トン部長は 君と話が したいそうだ
It seems Director Ton wants
to have a word with you.
ACCOUNTING DEPARTMENT
ご破算で願いましてはっと…
A fresh start...
（そろばんをはじく音）
（トン）いい音だ
It's a good sound, isn't it?
今は会計ソフトで カタカタ
やるのが 経理の仕事だが―
These days, accounting work
is clickety-clacked into software.
俺はパソコンってやつが
どうも苦手でな
But I've never been good with computers.
そろばんで
お前の教育のために―
I'm calculating, with this abacus,
会社が どれだけの金(かね)を
つぎ込んだのか―
how much money this company
has invested in your education.
ざっと計算してるところだ
ヘヘヘ…
（烈子）私も あのとき
頭の中で そろばんをはじきました
At the same time,
I was also doing math in my head.
値段のつけられない夢と
値段のつく現実を―
I weighed my priceless dream
against a costly reality,
てんびんの上に載せたのです
and the numbers were against me.
（烈子）ごめん… 私 やっぱり…
I'm sorry... I can't, after all.
Hey! Don't look so down!
ちょっと 落ち込まないでよ
ごめん
I'm sorry.
だから何で 烈子が謝んの？
Come on. Why are you apologizing?
いいんだよ 烈子には烈子の
生き方があるんだから
It's OK.
You've got your own way of living.
ウフッ… ねえ
Hey,
何で 私みたいにフラフラした
いいかげんなやつが―
do you know why someone irresponsible
like me can live on nothing but dreams?
夢だけ食って
生きていけるか分かる？
えっ？
何でだろう？
Why?
烈子みたいに堅実な人たちが
きちんと働いて―
It's thanks to reliable people like you
working hard and diligently paying taxes,
真面目に税金 払ったり―
経済 回したりしてくれてる
おかげじゃん
and keeping the economy
from tanking, right?
だから悪いけど 烈子は
真面目に堅実に生きてよ
Sorry, but I need you to live responsibly,
私らボンクラが
安心して フラフラできるように
so us blockheads can go
where the wind takes us.
ウフッ…
じゃあ 今日は私が おごる
OK, today is my treat.
（プー子）やりい！
All right!
（烈子･プー子）アハハハハハ…
（そろばんをはじく音）
（トン）オッホッホ…
This is quite an amount.
こりゃ 結構な額だな
本題だ
The real question is...
最近 お前の様子は おかしかった
Recently, you've been acting strange.
長年の勘で ピンときた俺は
内偵を進めた
I have investigated this
using my years of experience.
小宮！
Komiya!
From the following sites...
読み上げます！
転職支援サイト “マジ！？
私の月給やばくない！？”
A job changing site: "Seriously?
Isn't my monthly salary pathetic?"
質問サイト “辞表と退職届って
どう違うんですか？”
A Q&A site: "How do letters of
resignation and retirement differ?"
An AMA: "I just turned in my letter
of resignation. Ask me anything!"
まとめサイト―
“今日 退職届 出してきたけど
何か質問ある？”
-Continuing on, a self...
-Enough. You can stop there.
続きまして 独立支援…
（トン）
ああ もう そのへんでいいわ
身に覚えあんだろ？
You remember those, don't you?
今のは全て お前が残業中に
ネット上で クリンコした…
You "clinked" on all of those websites
on the internet, during overtime.
クリックです
It's "clicked"!
残業中にクリックしたサイトだ
You clicked on them during overtime.
社内端末からのアクセク…
You used a company device
to accesic... accesserate...
アクセグリル…
ルル…
Your browsing history is easily tracked
by the network manager.
社内端末からのアクセス履歴は―
ネットワーク管理社に照会すれば
一目瞭然なんですよ
（トン）辞めるつもりなんだろ？
You're planning to quit, aren't you?
What are you here to do?
To raise funds for self-employment?
会社に何をしに来てる？
独立資金作りか？
To look for a boyfriend
like you're at a singles party?
さもなきゃ 合コン気取りで
彼氏でも あさりに来たか！？
To "clink-clink" on this man and that man?
あっちの男 こっちの男を
クリンコ クリンコか～！
クリック クリックか～！
Click! Click!
まあ どっちにしても―
Well, whatever it is...
俺の言いたいことは１つだ
You've screwed yourself over.
俺は たった今から お前を―
As of now,
I've got a new name for you.
腰掛けと呼ぶ
You're "Short-timer" now.
（烈子）私 終わった～！
I'm finished!
Subtitle translation: John Haguewood
♪～
～♪